Guide to the Charles W. Poletti Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Subject Files, 1910-1991
  This extensive series holds information on a wide range of subjects relating to Poletti's military, political, and professional careers. Allied Military Government (AMG) files document his work as an allied military governor in Italy and include official orders, reports, correspondence, and descriptions of the state of the country. "Discrimination" Files contain a variety of material relating to Poletti's stance against discrimination, including press releases and campaign fliers focusing on his support of minority groups; discussions of the appointment of black employees to government positions; and correspondence and reports relating to the State War Council Committee on Discrimination in Employment, which investigated cases of discrimination in the workforce. They also contain a travel diary kept by philosopher Corliss Lamont, detailing his observations of racism on a 1926 trip through the South with Poletti, and his report based on the experience. Files on the New York World's Fair hold correspondence and reports outlining plans for the fair; photographs of Poletti and others at work on the project; and information on each of the country pavilions. They also hold public documents such as promotional fliers, postcards, maps, and articles. The series also contains material on Poletti's political campaigns and his work with the power authority, as well as notes and correspondence on a variety of issues such as low-cost housing and birth control. Files are arranged alphabetically by subject
  - Allied Military Government (AMG)
    - Poletti Military Service, 1939-1942 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Poletti 201 File, 1944-1945 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - General
      - 1943 January-1944 April, (4 Folders) (Box 17, Folder 10 to 13)
      - 1944 May-1948, (11 Folders) (Box 18, Folder 1 to 11)
      - 1944 January-1945 June, (4 Folders) (Box 60, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Administrative Instructions, 1943-1944, (8 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 1 to 8)
    - Monthly Reports, 1943-1945, (10 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 9 to 18)
    - Official Orders, 1943-1944, (4 Folders) (Box 20, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Proclamations, 1944 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Regional Orders, 1943-1945, (4 Folders) (Box 20, Folder 5 to 8)
      - Lombardy Region, 1945 June 1-27 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Special Orders, 1943 October 25-1944 February 15 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Clippings
      - 1943-1944, (3 Folders) (Box 20, Folder 10 to 12)
      - General, undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - 1945-1962, (4 Folders) (Box 21, Folder 2 to 4)
      - 1944 January-May (Box 60, Folder 7)
      - 1944 June-December (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - Oversize Broadsides and Maps, 1943-1945 (Box 63)
  - American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers (ASCAP), 1941 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Birth Control, 1941 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Campaign, 1960 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Campaign--General I, 1942 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Campaign, 1942
    - General II, 1942 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, 1941 August-1942 November, (2 Folders) (Box 22, Folder 2 to 3)
    - Dewey, Thomas E., 1942 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Jaeckle, Edwin F., 1942 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Contributions, 1942 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Statements and Handbills, 1942 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Statement of Operating Costs and Revenue from Power Plants, 1926-1940 (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Campaign, 1941
    - Clippings, 1941 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Speeches and Statements, 1941 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Campaign, 1940
    - Memos and Speeches, 1940 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Clippings, 1940 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Campaign, 1938 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1938 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Circulars, 1938, (2 Folders) (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Clippings, 20 October- November 1938, (2 Folders) (Box 24, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Clippings--Catholic Question, 1938 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Endorsements, 1938 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Press Releases, 1938 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Democratic Campaign Committee--Kings County Speakers Bureau, 1938 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Posters and Clippings, 1938 (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - Campaign--General, 1937 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Campaign--General, 1936 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Campaign--Circulars, 1936, (2 Folders) (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Campaign, 1932 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Catholic Charities, 1946-1947 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Charitable Contributions, 1946-1947 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Charles Poletti Power Project, 1991, (2 Folders) (Box 25, Folder 7 to 8)
  - Child Labor, 1937 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Christmas and Other Greeting Cards, 1948-1963 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Citizens Union Reports and Pamphlets, 1928-1937 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Cloak and Suit Industry--Congratulations Upon Appointment as Impartial Chairman, 1946 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Cloak and Suit Industry
    - Correspondence, 1946-1947 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Decisions and Contracts, 1946-1947 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Clippings, 1946-1947 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Commutations, 1943 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Gilmore Case, 1942-1943 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Hoffman, 1942-1943 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Statements and Speeches, 1942-1943, (2 Folders) (Box 26, Folder 7 to 8)
    - Crank Files, 1942-1943 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Clippings, 1942-1943 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Clippings, 1946-1961 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Constitutional Convention, 1938 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Constitutional Convention--Clippings, 1938 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Constitutional Convention--General, 1938 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, 1950s (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Decorations (Folder 3)
    - Gold Medal of the City of Rome, 1945 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Legion of Merit, undated (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Order of British Empire, 1910s-1940s (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Order of St. Gregory the Great, undated (Box 27)
    - Reserve Officers Association of U.S., undated (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Veterans of Foreign Wars, 1943 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Order of the Crown of Italy, undated, 1940s (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - Democratic National Convention, 1932 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Discrimination
    - General, 1938-1942, (5 Folders) (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Appointment of Negroes, 1939-1940 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Baseball Clippings, 1940 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - N.Y. State Guard, 1942 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - U.S. Military, 1940-1943 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - C. Poletti and Corliss Lamont Diary Trip through the South, 1926 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - "The Negro Problem"--Paper Result of Poletti Lamont Trip, by Corliss Lamont, 1926 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Eastchester (St. Paul's Church), 1938 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Extradition--D. Blythe, 1942 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Foreign Policy Association, 1920s (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Governor's Committee on Fiscal Organization in New York State, 1960s (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Governorship Clippings, 1942 December (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Housing
    - Correspondence, 1938 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - General and Clippings, 1938 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Speeches, 1937-1938 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Labor Relations Act, 1930s (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Legal Action--Vito Genovese in AMG, 1940s-1950s (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Legal and Business, 1940s-1950s (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Letterheads and Envelopes, undated (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Loyalty Oaths, 1930s (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Martin, George W.--Charges for Removal of, 1939 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Massena Power Line--Water Power, 1940s (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Membership Cards and Certificates, 1950s (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Masena Power Line, 1941-1942 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Mussolini, Benito, 1960s (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - National Youth Administration, 1930s-1950s (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper List--Circulation and Political Slant, undated (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - New York City--Employment Situation, 1942 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - New York City Politics--Clippings, 1939-1940 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - NY State
    - Defense and War Council
      - Applicants for Positions,1942 (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - General, 1940s undated (Box 30, Folder 6)
      - War Council Official Bulletin, 1942 July-December (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - Defense Bulletins, 1941-1942 (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - Printed Brochures, 1941 (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Printed Brochures, 1942 (Box 30, Folder 10)
      - Clippings, 1940-1942 (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - Trips (Folder 2)
        - Binghamton, Endicott, Hillcrest, Port Dickinson, 1941 (Box 31, Folder 3)
        - Buffalo, 1941-1942 (Box 31, Folder 4)
        - Elmira, Corning, Painted Post, 1941 (Box 31, Folder 5)
        - Long Island, 1941 (Box 31, Folder 6)
        - Massena, Canton, Ogdensburg, 1942 (Box 31, Folder 7)
        - Rochester, 1941 (Box 31, Folder 8)
        - Rome, Ilion, Utica, Oneida County, 1941 (Box 31, Folder 9)
        - Schenectady, 1941 (Box 31, Folder 10)
        - Syracuse, Onondaga County, 1941 (Box 31, Folder 11)
        - Utica, 1941-1942 (Box 31, Folder 12)
        - Westchester County, 1941 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Democratic Platform
      - Committee, 1958 August 1-17 (Box 31, Folder 14)
      - Committee, 1958 August 18-19 (Box 31, Folder 15)
      - General, 1958 July (Box 31, Folder 16)
      - Charles Poletti Memoranda, 1958 (Box 31, Folder 17)
      - 3rd Draft, 1958 (Box 31, Folder 18)
      - 1st and 2nd Drafts, 1942 (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - General, 1942 (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence, 1942 August 7-16 (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, 1942 August 17-27 (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - Draft Suggestions, 1942 (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - Drafts, 1942 (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - Reference Material and Clippings, 1942 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Democratic Platforms and Republican Platforms, 1932-1936 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Legislature, 1930s-1940s (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Politics--Clippings, 1943-1945 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Politics--Clippings, 1938-1940 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Niagara Falls Power Company, 1930s (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Power Authority, 1957-1970, (5 Folders) (Folder 3 to 7)
    - Maps, 1948, 1957 (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - General, 1951-1954, (6 Folders) (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, 1955-1958 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Of the State of New York--Dedication of the Poletti Power Projects, Astoria, Gift of C.P., 1982 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - St. Lawrence Seaway Power Project (Folder 4)
    - General, 1941-1942 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - General, 1938-1941, (4 Folders) (Box 35, Folder 1 to 4)
  - San Remo Strike, 1930s (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Savings Bank Life Insurance, 1930s (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - School Bus Transportation Bill, 1935-1937 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - School Bus Transportation Bill Clippings, 1935-1936, (2 Folders) (Box 35, Folder 8 to 9)
  - Supreme Court Appointment, 1937 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - School Bus Transportation Bill Clippings, 1935, (2 Folders) (Box 36, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Searches and Seizures, 1930s (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Special Secretary Applications, 1930s (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Supreme Court Clippings, 1937 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Trip to Italy--Clippings, 1947 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Trip to the Soviet Union--Report, 1927 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Trips to Europe, 1924-1947 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Vatican Statuette of St. Peter, 1949-1954 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Visiting Cards and Social Announcements, undated (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - WMCA Radio Broadcast--"Success Story," 1941 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Worlds Fair
    - General, 1959-1962, (5 Folders) (Box 37, Folder 2 to 6)
    - Christmas Greetings, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Christmas Greetings, 1962 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - General, 1963 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Directors Meeting, 1963 April (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - General, 1964, (4 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 4 to 7)
    - General, 1964, (3 Folders) (Box 39, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Christmas Greetings, 1964, (3 Folders) (Box 39, Folder 4 to 6)
    - Clippings, 1965 April, (5 Folders) (Box 40, Folder 1 to 5)
    - Directors Meeting, 1965 January (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - 1965 Reopening Press Kit, 1965 April (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - General, 1966 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Directors Meeting, 1965 January (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Bureau of International Expositions, 1960s (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Ground-breaking Ceremonies, 1960s (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - General, 1960s, (3 Folders) (Box 41, Folder 3 to 5)
    - International Exhibits, 1960s (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Sukarno Visit, undated (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Travel and Pavilions, 1960s (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Itineraries, 1960s (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - General, 1960s (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Bali, undated (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - China (Taiwan), 1960s (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Colombia, 1960s (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - India, 1960s (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Indonesia, 1960s (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Iran, 1960s (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Israel, 1960s (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Italy (Turin Center), 1960s (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Japan, 1960s (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Pakistan, 1960s (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - World Fair-Travel and Pavilions
    - Sierra Leone, 1960s (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Sudan, 1960s (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Spain, 1960s (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Sweden, 1960s (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Switzerland, 1960s (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Syria, 1960s (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Thailand, 1960s (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Togo, 1960s (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Trinidad, 1960s (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Tunis, 1960s (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Turkey, 1960s (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - United Arab Republic (Egypt), 1960s (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - Uruguay, 1960s (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Vatican City, 1960s (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Venezuela, 1960s (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - West African Trips, 1961 (Box 44, Folder 4)
- Series III: Harvard, 1920-1928
  This series documents Poletti's experiences as an undergraduate at Harvard and later as a law student. It includes his notes, examinations, and papers from classes in economics, English, government, philosophy, and psychology, among others. It also holds three diaries covering Poletti's time in college and graduate school. Materials are filed by subject and document type.
  - Harvard College
    - Economics--Notes and Exams, 1920s, (7 Folders) (Box 44, Folder 5 to 11)
    - English A, Papers, undated (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - English A, Exams, undated (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - English A, Themes, 1920s (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Government 1, Notes and Exams, 1920s (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Philosophy A, Exams and Papers, undated (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Philosophy A, Notes, 1920s (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Psychology B, Notes, 1920s (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Psychology 16, Exams and Papers, 1920s (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Exams, Notes, Paper and a Diary, undated (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - "The Attitude of the American Government…" undated (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - "History of Albania 1914-1922," 1923 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Harvard Law School--Paper: "The Judicial Review of Immigration…" 1920s (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Harvard College and Harvard Law--Diaries, 1925-1928 (3 diaries) (Box 56, Folder 7)
- Series IV: Legal Briefs, 1940-1964
  This small series contains legal briefs for cases on which Poletti served as an attorney. Some include Poletti's annotations. They are filed chronologically.
  - Legal Briefs, 1940s-1948, (4 Folders) (Folder 4 to 7)
    - 1955-1964, (5 Folders) (Box 47, Folder 1 to 5)
- Series V: Speeches and Press Releases, 1937-1947
  This series is comprised primarily of campaign speeches given by Poletti at conventions and meetings, or over the radio. They cover topics such as public housing, discrimination, labor legislation, and civil and religious liberty. Several speeches present Poletti's experiences working with Herbert. H. Lehman. Files contain both drafts and completed speeches, arranged chronologically. An index can be found within each folder. The series also holds press releases announcing Poletti's actions as Lieutenant Governor and as acting Governor of New York, filed chronologically.
  - Press Releases, 1939-1942, (4 Folders) (Box 47)
  - Speeches, 1937-1938, (2 Folders) (Folder 10 to 11)
    - 1939-1941, (8 Folders) (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - 1941-1942, (6 Folders) (Box 49, Folder 1 to 6)
    - 1945-1947, (3 Folders) (Box 50, Folder 1 to 3)
    - General, undated (Box 50, Folder 4)
- Series VI: General, undated (Box 50)
  The files in this series hold family manuscripts in Italian, notes, and other personal documents
  - Correspondence, undated (Folder 5)
  - Family Manuscripts in Italian, undated (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Notes and Memos, undated (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Notes in Italian, undated (Box 50, Folder 8)
- Series VII: Jean E. Poletti, 1931-1964
  This series is comprised of letters written by Poletti's wife, Jean Knox Ellis Poletti, written during the early years of their marriage. It also contains seven travel diaries chronicling her visits to many countries during the 1960s.
  - Correspondence
    - 1931-1934 ( Folders 1-2) (Box 50, Folder 9 to 10)
    - 1931-1935, (6 Folders) (Box 51, Folder 1 to 6)
  - Travel Diaries
    - 1960-1964, (3 Folders) (Box 51, Folder 7 to 9)
  - Passport, 1960s (Box 52, Folder 1)
- Series VIII: Articles by and About Charles Poletti, circa 1930-1970
  Articles written by Charles Poletti typically touch on political topics. Those written about him generally regard his post in Italy immediately following World War II. Articles on Poletti's career can also be found in Series XIII: Clipping Books.
  - General, circa 1930-1970, (4 Folders) (Box 52, Folder 2 to 5)
  - 1945-1960 (Box 61, Folder 13)
- Series IX: Photographs, 1920-1983
  Some of these photographs are records of Charles Poletti's time in Italy during and following the Second World War, when he served in the Allied Military Government as a civil affairs officer. It also contains portraits of other politicians from the time, and images of Poletti with various members of his family, including his wife Jean. Several folders contain images that pertain to the 1964 World's Fair in New York City in 1964. Photographs can also be found throughout Series I: Correspondence.
  - Allied Military Government, circa 1945 (Box 52, Folder 6 to 8)
  - Allied Military Government, circa 1945 (Box 53)
  - Davis, John W., undated (Box 53)
  - Harriman, Averell, undated (Box 53)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., undated (Box 53)
  - Lehman, Herbert H., undated (Box 53)
  - Poletti, Charles--Portraits, undated, (2 Folders) (Box 53)
  - Poletti, Charles and Jean E., undated (Box 53)
  - Poletti, Charles and Jean with Children, undated (Box 53)
  - Poletti Family, 1920-1983 (Box 53)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., undated (Box 53)
  - Stimson, Henry L., undated (Box 53)
  - World's Fair
    - Album I, circa 1964, (2 Folders) (Box 53)
    - Album I-IV, circa 1964, (6 Folders) (Box 54, Folder 1 to 6)
    - Album IV-V, 1963-1965, (3 Folders) (Box 55, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Memorabilia Album (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - World's Fair Miscellaneous, 1964-1965 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous, 1924-1965, (2 Folders) (Box 55, Folder 8 to 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1937-1940 (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Negatives, undated (Box 58)
  - Harvard College Class of 1924 Reunion, 1939 (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - Group Photos and Statue, 1933-1936 (Box 60, Folder 12)
  - Allied Military Government, 1944-1945 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Coat and Suit Industry, 1946 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Turkey Cabinet Luncheon, 1932 (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Poletti, Charles--Portraits, 1939 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - World's Fair Album II--Aerial View of Grounds, 1964 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - World's Fair Album III--General, circa 1964 (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - World's Fair Album IV--Aerial Views of Grounds, circa 1964 (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Cave Ardeatine Massacre--Photo Album, 1944 (Box 63)
  - "For Those Who Produced the New York World's Fair, 1964-1965"--Photo Album, 1965, (3 Folders) (Box 64, Folder 1 to 3)
  - Poletti's Visit to Asuncion, Paraguay--Photo Album, 1961 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Korea Trip--Photo Album, undated (Box 65)
- Series X: Memorabilia, circa 1915-1965
  This collection of materials including address books, diaries, passports, campaign buttons, and other personal effects belonging to Charles Poletti, as well as certificates and plaques awarded to him.
  - Address and Date Books, 1929-1943 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Certificates, 1938-1965, (2 Folders) (Box 56, Folder 2 to 3)
  - Passports, circa 1915 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Regalia, undated (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Medals and Buttons, circa 1920-1960 (Box 58)
  - Cartoons by Rollin Kirby, 1938 (Box 60, Folder 13)
  - Certificates, 1930-1969 (Box 60, Folder 14)
  - Diplomas, 1926 (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - Certificates, 1933-1953 (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - Leather Desk Set taken by Charles Poletti from Mussolini's Desk at Villa Feltrinella, Lake Garda, Italy--Includes Unidentified Photographs and Correspondence in Italian, 1945 (Box 62)
  - Bound Volume of Newspaper Sicilia Liberata with Inscription to Poletti, 1944 (Box 62)
  - New York World's Fair Guestbook,1964-1965 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - N.Y. World's Fair--Banner, 1964 (Box 59)
  - Wartime Postcards, 1942-1945 (Box 73)
  - Postcards, circa 1945 (Box 74)
  - Plaques
    - Coordinating Council of 213 Cooperatives, 1957 (Box 78)
    - Clothing Manufacturers Association, 1963 (Box 78)
  - Marble Bust of Poletti (Box Lehman Suite)
- Series XI: Audiotapes and Films, 1939-1964
  The audio tapes and films in this series pertain to the 1939 and 1964 New York World's Fairs. They include a speech Poletti gave about the 1939 Fair and interview with Poletti about his involvement in the 1964 Fair, among others.
  - Audiotapes
    - Barry Gray Show, 1964 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Foreign Press Conference, 1963 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Korean Industrial Exposition, 1962 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Overseas Press Club, 1963 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - C. Poletti Interview, 1964 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - C. Poletti Speech--1939 World's Fair (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Film
    - "To Build a Fair" (Box 57, Folder 6)
- Series XII: Records, 1937-1964
  This series holds speeches and interviews with Poletti recorded on record albums, including talks on low-cost housing, anti-corruption, and a report on the 1964 World's Fair. It also contains a number of popular music records owned by Poletti.
  - Testimonial Dinner for Charles Poletti with Speech by Herbert H. Lehman, 1937 February 25 (8 records) (Box 75)
  - Poletti Speeches
    - "Partnership in Nationwide Low-Cost Housing," 1938 February 2 (2 records) (Box 75)
    - "Pythianism and Americanism," 1939 February 19 (2 records) (Box 75)
    - Memorial Service for Colonel Vigo, 1939 February 24 (2 records) (Box 75)
    - "Anti-Corruption Program," 1939 February 25 (Box 75)
    - "Legislation and Government," 1939 February 25 (3 records, 2 copies) (Box 75)
    - "New York State Czechoslovak Day," 1940 March 7 (Box 75)
    - State Police Conference, 1940 August 13 (5 records) (Box 76)
    - Poletti Gubernatorial Inauguration, 1942 December 2 (2 records) (Box 76)
    - Unknown Poletti Speech, 1947 September 10 (Box 76)
  - "World's Fair Report"--Interview Featuring Bill Berns, Charles Poletti, Douglas Beaton, and Gates Davison, 1963 July 26 (Box 76)
  - Robert Moses at Massena, N.Y., 1963 September 18 (Box 76)
  - "The Tex McCrary Program"--Interview, 1964 February 28 (Box 76)
  - Popular Music, circa 1940-1960 (15 records) (Box 77)
- Series XIII: Clipping Books, 1933-1948
  Series XIII is comprised of clipping books containing newspaper articles about Poletti. Most were collected systematically by press clipping agencies, and the 1940-1942 books contain a near complete record of Poletti's appearances in New York newspapers. Books are arranged chronologically.
  - Scrapbook I, 1933-1936 (Box 66)
  - Scrapbook II-III, 1934-1937 (2 scrapbooks) (Box 67)
  - Campaign, 1938 (Box 72)
  - 1938 Campaign Clippings and Photographs, 1938 (Box 66)